(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-27T05:02:50.508930",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
いたずらに君をずっと見ていたわけじゃない
It's not like I've just been teasingly watching you.
僕の考えをあててごらんよ
Try and guess what I'm thinking.
些細な仕草
Small gestures,
視線 瞬き 君はもう手のひらに
gazes, blinks—you're already in the palm of my hand.
剥き出しのtrapなんてかかる訳ないわ
There's no way I'd fall for such an obvious trap.
甘い言葉にも惑わされない
I won't be swayed by sweet words either.
心の奥の奥の奥まで見透かしちゃうよ
I'll see right through to the very depths of your heart.
Looking, seeking, touching, feeling,
Why you know?
I know it.
Looking, seeking, touching, feeling,
Understand?
Meaning, meaning of love
“Are you ready?”
"Are you ready?"
自覚ないでしょうね
You have no self-awareness, do you?
思い通りに君は動かされている事！
You're being made to move just as planned!
単純じゃないの 駆け引きのhintを全て見落とさないで
It's not that simple. Don't overlook a single hint.
華々し過ぎておなかがよじれるよ
It's so glamorous it twists my stomach in knots.
次に君は何を選ぶ？
What will you choose next?
Meaning of love, meaning of love
加速していく二人の鼓動
Our heartbeats accelerate.
Meaning of love, meaning of love
心理戦は次のステージへ
The psychological battle moves to the next stage.
うつろなその目に私はどう映るの
How do I look in those vacant eyes?
とても煌びやかでまるでシンデレラ
So dazzling, just like Cinderella.
突き刺さる視線 ゾキンと感じて
Feeling your piercing gaze give me chills,
君に余裕見せつけて
showing off my composure to you.
頭が次の次の次まで見透かさないとね
I've got to see right through to the very next steps ahead.
Looking, seeking, touching, feeling...
いつもみんなの中で敵にするために
To make an enemy out of everyone always,
欲望もさらけ出してる本当
baring all my desires for real.
離れていく世界のロジックを
The logic of a world drifting away—
きみは楽しめるかな
I wonder if you can enjoy it.
きみにとって重要な日は
The important days to you,
すべて知ってくれ
please know all of them.
あと戻りできないステージへ
To a stage of no return!
混ざっているでしょう ここにいる意味さえも
We must be mixed up, even the meaning of being here,
切り札はそれぞれ 互いの手札に
each trump card in each other's hands.
頭とところで暴き出して 胸を打ち抜け
Exposing it in our heads and hearts, shoot right through my chest!
自信くないでしょね 思いどおりに
You're not confident, are you? Just as you wanted,
きみは動かされていること
you are being moved.
単純じゃないのさ 駆け引きのヒントを
It's not simple, hints for bargaining,
すべて知ってる いつも
knowing everything always.
謎の中の癖にすることで
By making it part of the mystery,
理解できた愛の形を
I understood the shape of love.
どっかの誰かに仕留められていても
Even if brought down by someone somewhere,
最高に笑うきみと
with you smiling at your best,
家族していく 二人だけのコードで
we'll become family with just the two of us' code.
真実んわすりろ ステージへ
To the true forgotten stage!
片っぽ好きだったのか 鐘が鳴る
Did you love one-sidedly? A bell rings.
今は戦うだけ やわい顔映した可愛い前髪
Now we just fight, cute bangs reflecting a fragile face.
波の上 広い飲むのは中毒患者 広い空なのに奇妙な予感だ
On the waves, drinking is an addict; despite the wide sky, it's a strange premonition.
そうか簡単な天井を決めてなかったんだ
I see, it's simple: we hadn't decided on a ceiling.
それが団結できない要因だ あなた含め船員は5人だ
That's the reason we can't unite—including you, the crew is 5 people.
候補はこれで全員か 3人不要でいいか
Is this everyone for candidates? Are 3 people unnecessary?
奪い合いなんか異常だ
Fighting over things is abnormal.
多数決が理想さ みんな自分に入れるか
Democracy is ideal—do they all vote for themselves?
というわけでサイレンス きみ次第
So, silence, it's up to you.
誰にしたって気にしない 最後の航海だから行き先は選び放題
Whomever you choose, I don't care; since it's our last voyage, destinations are yours to pick.
プリーズ ミスターサイレンス どうして どうしてラベルのがきみしかないないなにんだ
Please, Mr. Silence, why, why is it only you who can label?
お願いチューミー お願いチューミー
Please choose me, please choose me.
ほら早く 今日中に
Come on, hurry, within today.
お願いチューミー チューミー
Please choose me, choose me.
きみが今日選んでくれないとなんもできない考えてくれないと心配に
If you don't choose me today, nothing can be done; if you don't think about it, I get worried.
感じちゃうんだ こんなところで迷ってると沈むよ深海に
I feel it—getting lost in a place like this, we'll sink into the deep sea.
An error occurred in this system.
沈むよ深海に
Sinking into the deep sea...
濡れて気づいた 震える身体
Getting wet, I noticed my trembling body.
ふるえるからだが あふれてきちゃった
My trembling body just overflowed...
隙間どこからか 穴が空いたんだ
From somewhere in the gaps, a hole opened up.
焦臭くて あどうして治ってるのが
It smells burnt, ah, why is it fixing itself
君にしかな いんだ
only for you?
おねがいシューリー、シュリー
We will sail the seven seas...
さあ ほら今すぐ シュリー
Now come on, right now, with glee...
塞いで熱中して 熱中して
Seal it up, get absorbed, get absorbed,
君が欲しくて触れない そんなもできない
I want you so much I can't even touch you.
感じちゃうそろそろ限界し 重要なもの探しにかなわない
I'm reaching my limit soon, searching for what's important...
大好きな夢の旅 新世界に 君がいないと意味がない
On my favorite dream journey, without you in this new world, it means nothing!
考えなくれないと心配に 感じちゃうんだ こんなとこで 迷ってるっといけないよ絶対に
If you don't think about me, I get worried and feel lost in a place like this—
いけないよ絶対に
you absolutely mustn't!
海賊ならよほ 踊れ踊れでよほさ
If you're pirates, Yotho! Dance and shake, Yotho!
今朝のもとへ 宝鐘海賊団
Head towards the morning, Houshou Pirates!
宝鐘海賊団だー！
Houshou Pirates!
出航！ Ahoy!
Set sail! Ahoy!
踊るAhoy! 見るAhoy!
Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
全速全進だ 進め！
Full speed ahead, march on!
太陽は燦々 大航海日和だ歌え！
The sun is brilliant, a fine day for a grand voyage, sing out!
最高潮のテンション 波の音にのって 音符を紡いで ガルスタキ！
Peak tension, riding the waves, weaving notes, Garstaki!
おかげ兄貴がハッピー 踊らせてはどー君 キラキラ！
Thanks to you big bros, we're happy, making you dance, sparkling!
山奥ボロボロ マイハウスで夢を見て
Dreaming deep in a rundown mountain house...
神様 いつかこのマリンを本物の海賊にしてください！
Dear God, please turn this Marine into a real pirate someday!
声を上げて さあ出航だ 我ら宝鐘
Raise your voices, time to set sail, we are the Houshou
海賊団だ 盆暮れ片手に旗を上げ
Pirates, raising flags with both hands during holidays,
この海をジャックしちゃおう 夜空続いでおいで
let's jack this ocean, follow into the night sky,
共によほよほ 叫ぼう ああ 最高の日々
shouting together Yotho Yotho, ah, what a supreme day!
ようこそ 我が船へ
Welcome aboard my ship!
踊るAhoy! 見るAhoy!
Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
1, 2, 3, 4, バババー！
1, 2, 3, 4, Ba-ba-bar!
熱く 語ろうよファッション 想いを解き放て
Passionately talk about fashion, unleash your feelings,
熱く きらめくファッション 形から入るタイプです発射！
passionately sparkling fashion, we're the type to start from appearance, fire!
沈黙の前へ 走れ 駆け込んでいけ じゅんじゃなくても照れるわ
Before the silence, run and dash in, even if it's not smooth I get shy,
キラキラ！
sparkling!
びんがり汗もしたたるイイ女 だが しかし
A fine woman dripping with sweat, but however—
神様 船長は精神病だと罰せられたのですね、はにゃあ！
Dear God, the captain was punished because she's mentally ill, hannya!
奪われたら 取り戻せ それが保証 海賊だ
If it's stolen, take it back, that's the Houshou Pirates!
君たちとなら 見つけ出す 伝説のエルドラド
With you guys, we'll find the legendary Eldorado!
夜空のしけりゃ 歌えよほ よほ 離さない
If the night sky is rough, sing Yotho Yotho, won't let go,
この景色 大切な仲間よ
this scenery, my precious comrades!
宴だ 宴だ 騒げや騒げ！
Feast, feast, make some noise!
踊るAhoy! 見るAhoy!
Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
同じおホラルの男たちよ さっさと片手に生きまっしょ！
Hey guys, let's live with one hand fast!
それAhoy! Ahoy! ... 宝鐘マリン！
That's Ahoy! Ahoy! ... Houshou Marine!
世界で一番 メスガキメスガキ！
The number one brat in the world, mesugaki mesugaki!
エロガキエロガキ！ ボンギュッボーン！
Erogaki erogaki! Bon-gyu-bon!
お嬢ちゃん パンツ何色…？
Little lady, what color are your panties...?
熱から熱から 戻り戻り 喉まスゴン！
From heat to heat, returning, throat is gon!
船長の素敵んこ 行ってみたい？
Want to visit the Captain's cozy spot?
アハハハッ
Ahahaha!
もっともっともっと！
More, more, more!
ウフフフッ
Ufufu!
もっともっともっと！
More, more, more!
セクシーに！
Be sexy!
イチャマイシング！
Flirty-charming!
もっともっともっと！
More, more, more!
タッチューの！
Tachuu's!
テリテリつー！
Teri-teri-tsu!
もっともっともっと！
More, more, more!
萌えのエキス！
Moe extract!
もっともっともっと！
More, more, more!
出会って5秒で！ 撃ち抜くぞ！
5 seconds after meeting you! I'll shoot you through!
あーもう！船長は君達をそんな風に育てた覚えはありません！
Oh geez! The Captain doesn't remember raising you guys like that!
本当にー？ねぇー？そうだぞ！
Really? Hey? That's right!
立てば地蔵、座れば地蔵、歩く姿は…
Standing, you're Jizo; sitting, you're Jizo; walking, you look like...
夢の民よこの船で航海なんてさせない
People of dreams, I won't let you sail away on this ship!
君達のおかげで私は船長になれるから！
Because thanks to you guys, I can be the Captain!
砕け船長コール！
Smash that Captain call!
打てーい！
Fire!
鳴らせ船長サロウ！撃てーい！
Ring the Captain's salow! Fire!
声を上げてさあ出航だ
Raise your voices, now set sail,
狙え捕獲だ 消毒だ
aim for the catch, sterilize!
奮発！片手に旗を掲げ
Splurge! Hold a flag in one hand
この海を独占しよう
and monopolize this sea!
よそ見してないでおいで
Don't look away, come here,
共に行こうよ
let's go together!
叫ぼう Ah 最高の日々
Shout, Ah, the best days!
ようこそ我が船へ
Welcome to my ship,
welcome to my ship!
宝鐘の海賊団
Houshou's pirate crew,
Houshou's pirate crew!
それでは行きますよー！
Here we go~!
出航ー！
Set sail~!
はーい、ということで！はい、たて続けに3曲聞いていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Ha~i, so! Yes, you listened to 3 songs back-to-back. Thank you very much!
君たち、あほーい！はい。
You guys, ahoi! Yes.
ってことでね、ちょっとまずさ、君たち、ま、気づくこと、ちょっと2つくらいないかな、何か。気づいてほしいな。コメントで指摘されたいな。
So, first of all, don't you guys notice... maybe about two things? I want you to notice. I want to be pointed out in the comments.
じゃあその1！見てください！
Now, number one! Please take a look!
このステージ！わぁ！ちょっとね、あの船長風に作ってもらいました。どうですか？素敵でしょう？
This stage! Wow! They made it in the Captain's style. How is it? Isn't it wonderful?
今日はここで歌って踊ってしていきたいと思うのでね、存分に見っていってください。
I want to sing, dance, and perform here today, so please enjoy looking at it to your heart's content.
もう一個あるよね？気付かれたい、乙女心。
There's another one, right? I want you to notice, a maiden's heart.
さあ、この帽子で！ちょっとね、船長の頭があまりにも丸いのでね。
Now, with this hat! Well, the Captain's head is just too round.
ちょっとつけてもらいました。どうですか？確かに丸い頭も可愛いけど、この尖り耳が可愛いでしょう？これでね、より海賊感が増したかと思うのですが！
So they attached it for me. How is it? Sure, a round head is cute, but aren't these pointy ears cute? With this, I think the pirate feel has increased even more!
そして今日はね、今日は何のライブですか？はい。
And today, what kind of live is today? Yes.
今日のライブはマリン出航お披露ライブということで、ま、実はもうお披露目、ね、ちょっとサードライブでやったんですけど、まだ見れてない人もいるんじゃないかなあ。
Today's live is the "Marine Departure Debut Live", so, well, actually we already debuted it, right, in the 3rd live, but there might be people who haven't seen it yet.
今日初めて聴くっていう人もいるんじゃないかなあ。船長にとってもうとっても、とっても大事な1曲になっていますので、今日はしっかり聴いてくださいよ。
There might be people hearing it for the first time today. Since it's a very, very important song for the Captain, please listen carefully today.
そしてね、この後、まさしもついてるかもしれないが、22時になんかプレミア公開がありますよね？ちょっとすごいね、すごいことになってるから、もうそこも絶対見てほしい！重大発表のひとつです。
And, after this, Masashi might be attached too, but at 22:00, there's a premiere release, right? It's amazing, something incredible is happening, so I definitely want you to see that too! It's one of the major announcements.
てなわけで、この後はちょっとやっぱ1人じゃね、さすかに寂しいなと思ったのでいろんなホロメンと歌っていきたいと思いますので、それではゲストパートに…うーん、しゅっこうー！
So, after this, being alone would honestly feel a bit lonely, so I want to sing with various Holomem, so then, to the guest part... um, shukkou~!
マイハウスは段ボール
My house is cardboard
ニューハウスエレクトロハウス
New house, electro house
トラックドライバー通勤ラッシュ
Truck driver, commuter rush
アップなロードはテンションMAX
Up road is tension MAX
ハウスダストノンフィクション
House dust, nonfiction
花粉症にはマスクメロン
A muskmelon for hay fever
カーソル待ってよクラクション
Cursor, wait for the horn
ほらクリックリリックトラックメイカー
Hey, click, lyric, track maker
お洒落の極地だファッションセンター
The height of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げてクラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands and clap your hands up
ジャージにワイシャツ絶対変
Jersey and dress shirt, totally weird
M・I・D・Iトラックメイカー
M-I-D-I track maker
お洒落の聖地だファッションセンター
Sanctuary of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げてクラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands and clap your hands up
納期は明日だ絶対徹夜
Delivery date is tomorrow, absolute all-nighter
エビデイエビナイトラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, track maker
ロリ顔コンプなつるぺったっぷ
Loli-face complex, flat-chested
ホップでステップダブルステップ
Hop and step, double step
フロアのあいつはロボットダンス
That guy on the floor is robot dancing
お酒も入ってそこそこナイス
With some drinks, it's pretty nice
ネクタイ緩めた今こそチャンス
Loosening my tie, now's the chance
マイハウス is 段ボール
My house is made of cardboard
Newハウス エレクトロハウス
New house, electro house
トラックドライバー 通勤ラッシュ
Truck driver, commuter rush
アップなロードは テンションMAX
Upped road, tension MAX
ハウスダスト ノンフィクション
House dust, non-fiction
花粉症には マスクメロン
A muskmelon for hay fever
カーソル待ってよ クラクション
Wait for the cursor, horn
ほら クリック リリック トラックメイカー
Hey, click lyrics, trackmaker
お洒落の極みだ ファッションセンター
The height of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
ジャージにワイシャツ 絶対変だ
Jersey and a dress shirt, definitely weird
M・I・D・I トラックメイカー
M-I-D-I trackmaker
お洒落の聖地だ ファッションセンター
The sanctuary of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
納期は明日だ 絶対徹夜
The deadline is tomorrow, absolute all-nighter
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, trackmaker
眠気のピークに カフェイン投下
Dropping caffeine at the peak of sleepiness
お洒落の極みだ ファッションセンター
The height of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
チャーヂにワイシャツ 絶対変だ
Charging with a dress shirt, definitely weird
M・I・D・I トラックメイカー
M-I-D-I trackmaker
お洒落の聖地だ ファッションセンター
The sanctuary of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
脳キワ明日だ 絶対徹夜
Brain's edge tomorrow, absolute all-nighter
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, trackmaker
お洒落の極みだ ファッションセンター
The height of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
チャーヂにワイシャツ 絶対変だ
Charging with a dress shirt, definitely weird
M・I・D・I トラックメイカー
M-I-D-I trackmaker
お洒落の聖地だ ファッションセンター
The sanctuary of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, trackmaker
お洒落の極みだ ファッションセンター
The height of fashion, fashion center
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, clap your hands up
チャーヂにワイシャツ 絶対変だ
Charging with a dress shirt, definitely weird
M・I・D・I トラックメイカー
M-I-D-I trackmaker
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, trackmaker
はあ、はあ！終わったねー！
Phew, phew! That's done!
かなた、ありがとう！
Kanata, thank you!
いやーお疲れ様です！
Man, good work!
今回のね、そのインドア系ならトラックメイカーは
This time, 'Indoor-kei nara Track Maker'...
かなたが選んでくれたんだよね！
...is a song Kanata chose for us!
そうなんです。ちょっとね、僕たちの可愛い可愛い萌え声に会うかなってと思ってね。
That's right. I thought it would match our cute, adorable moe voices.
そうだね！マリンちゃんも頑張ってすごい萌え声で歌ってた！
True! Marine-chan also worked hard and sang with a super moe voice!
うわ、もうキッツ！
Ugh, so cringe!
いやいやいや、皆さん、あの、すいませんね、マリンちゃんのちょっと、あの、無理した萌え声をお届けした形になって申し訳ございませんでした！
No no no, everyone, sorry for delivering Marine-chan's slightly forced moe voice!
キツくございま…キツいもう！
It wasn't... It was super cringe!
でもマリンちゃん今日は、今日はね、おめでとう日なので！
But Marine-chan, today is a celebratory day!
あ、じゃあね、喧嘩はやめよう、喧嘩はね。
Ah, well then, let's stop fighting, fighting is...
そうだよ、喧嘩しないで仲良くで終わろう。
That's right, let's not fight and end on good terms.
あ、でもさ、これさ、歌みた出すまであるよね、これ。
Ah, but you know, we might even release a cover of this.
神だから、神曲だから、ちょっとこれ形に残したいなって思っている。
It's god-tier, a divine song, so I want to leave it as a record.
ねえ、分かる！バズるかもしれないなっていう伏線を出しながら。
Right, I know! While dropping hints that it might blow up.
じゃ、仲良く終わろっか！
Well then, let's end on good terms!
ゆらりゆらり揺れている 乙女心ピンチ！
Swaying back and forth, a maiden's heart is in a pinch!
かなりかなりヤバイのよ 助けてダーリン！ クラクラリン
It's pretty dangerous, help me, darling! Dizzy, dizzy!
何もかもが新しい世界に来ちゃったわ
Everything has arrived in a brand new world!
たくさんのドキドキ 乗りこえろ！ 踏みこえろ！ イイクゾ！
Overcome all the heart-pounding moments! Step over them! Let's go!
バラライカ バラライラカ バラライラカイカイ！
Balalaika, balala laika, balala-laila-kai-kai!
この想いは止められない！
I can't stop these feelings!
もっと乙女ちっく パワー きらりーん
More maiden-chic power, sparkling!
ちょっと危険なカンジ
A slightly dangerous vibe!
バラライカ バラライラカ バラライラカイカイ！
Balalaika, balala laika, balala-laila-kai-kai!
もうドキドキ止められない！
I still can't stop my heart from pounding!
もっとドラマチック 恋 ハレルヤ
More dramatic love, hallelujah!
二人だけの バラライカ！
Our very own balalaika!
バラライカ バラライラカ バラライラカイカイ！
Balalaika, balala laika, balala-laila-kai-kai!
もうドキドキ止められない！
I still can't stop my heart from pounding!
ゆらりゆらり揺れている
Swaying back and forth,
少女心ピ〜ンチ!
my girl's heart is in a pinch!
かなりかなりヤバいのよ
This is pretty dangerous,
たすけてダーリン!クラクラリン
Help me, darling! I'm feeling dizzy.
何もかもが新しい世界にきちゃったわ
Everything has jumped into a brand new world!
たくさんのドキドキ乗りこえろ!ふみこえろ!いくぞ!
Overcome all the heartbeats! Step over them! Let's go!
バラライカ バララライカ バラ ラライ カイカイ!
Balalaika, balala laika, bala-laila-kai-kai!
この想いは止められない!
I can't stop these feelings!
もっと少女ちっくパワー きらりり〜ん
A more girlish power, shining bright!
ちょっと危険なカンジ
It's a slightly dangerous feeling.
バラライカ バララライカ バラ ラライ カイカイ!
Balalaika, balala laika, bala-laila-kai-kai!
もうドキドキ止められない
This pounding heart can't be stopped,
もっとドラマチック恋ハレルヤ
a more dramatic love, hallelujah!
二人だけの バラライカ!
A balalaika just for the two of us!
すごくすごく近づいて少女心チャ〜ンス!
Getting super close, girl's heart chance!
ハートハート飛び出そう
My heart is about to jump out,
おねがいダーリン!ハラハラリン
Please, darling! I'm all aflutter.
あなただけを見つめているワタシにしらんぷり?
Pretending not to notice me gazing only at you?
気づいてほしいのよ ドキミキ!ヤキミキ!スキヨ!
I want you to notice! I'm excited, impatient, I love you!
バラライカ バララライカ バラ ラライ カイカイ!
Balalaika, balala laika, bala-laila-kai-kai!
その秘密を教えてよ
Tell me your secret!
もっと少女ちっくモード きらりり〜ん
A more girlish mode, shining bright,
やっぱり笑顔がステキ
After all, your smile is wonderful.
バラライカ バララライカ バラ ラライ カイカイ!
Balalaika, balala laika, bala-laila-kai-kai!
よそみしちゃダメだめよ
Don't you dare look away!
もっとロマンチック 恋シャラランラ
A more romantic love, sha-ran-ran,
奏でたいの バラライカ!
I want to play the balalaika!
女の子はいつでも夢見る少女なの
Girls are always dreaming maidens,
ピュアピュアな心で恋して!愛して!S!O!S.O.S!
Fall in love with a pure heart! Love me! S!O!S.O.S!
バラライカ バララライカ バラ ラライ カイカイ!
Balalaika, balala laika, bala-laila-kai-kai!
この想いは止められない!
I can't stop these feelings!
もっと少女ちっくパワー きらりり〜ん
A more girlish power, shining bright,
ちょっと危険なカンジ
It's a slightly dangerous feeling.
バラライカ バララライカ バラ ラライ カイカイ!
Balalaika, balala laika, bala-laila-kai-kai!
もうドキドキ止められない
This pounding heart can't be stopped,
もっとドラマチック恋ハレルヤ
a more dramatic love, hallelujah!
二人だけの バラライカ!
A balalaika just for the two of us!
はーい！ということで、メルちゃんに来てもらいましたー！
Ha-i! So, we invited Mel-chan to join us!
こんかっぷ！夜空メルだよ〜！
Konkap! It's Yozora Mel!
ああメルちゃんありがとう！ありがとー！
Ah, Mel-chan, thank you! Thank you!
はい、今回曲の候補色々あったけど、結局これにした決め手は何でしょう？
We had various song candidates, but what made you decide on this one?
それはやっぱり、マリンもメルもニコ中だからさー！
Well, of course, because both Marine and Mel are Nico addicts!
そうだね！
That's right!
ところでメルちゃん、せんちょの家に泊まりに来た時さ、勝負下着を持ってきたのにマリンが即寝してショックだったって本当？
By the way, Mel, when you stayed over at Senchou's, is it true you brought sexy lingerie, but Marine passed out immediately and you were shocked?
本当だよ！マリンのバカ！メルの勝負下着どうしてくれるの？
It's true! Marine, you idiot! What are you gonna do about my sexy lingerie?
ど…ごめんね、メル。
S... Sorry, Mel.
マリン？今からあの日のリベンジしよう。
Marine? Let's get our revenge for that day right now.
ここ寝そべって、ここ。ねて、早く。
Lie down here, right here. Sleep, hurry up.
ここで？まじか。ここここ、はい。
Right here? Seriously? Right here, yes.
もう、なにもないじゃん。はい、寝て寝て。
Geez, there's nothing here. Okay, lie down, lie down.
はい、いくよ。メル、マリン。
Okay, here we go. Mel... Marine...
いいよ、きて。あれ？
It's good, come over. Huh?
マリン？あれ？また寝てるじゃん！バカ！
Marine? Huh? You're sleeping again! Idiot!
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-hearted, you'll be K.O.'d.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we prepare for the curtain rise?
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね
Whether crying or laughing, love me.
ほら Say No 低音響かかせろ
Come on, say no, make the bass rumble.
なんだか…ってつまらないこともあるでしょう
Must be some boring things like "somehow..."
ロンリー論理のノート ハンディ本気脱走
Lonely-logical notes, handy and earnest escape.
やんなんちゃって泥に Bad ご法度だろがも溺れて堕ちて
Fed up with it, bad in the mud. Even if it's taboo, let's drown and fall.
そろそろいっか もっと頑張って
Is it about time? Try harder.
アガるまでもっと頑張って 繋がろひとりよりふたり
Try harder until you get hyped. Let's connect, rather than one, two.
増えたら安心 心配ないや Alright 任せて Don't mind
If it increases, you're safe, no worries. Alright, leave it to me, don't mind.
波あり難問 みんなで乗っかっちゃえば
Wavy difficult problems, if everyone gets on them,
案外さくっと行っちゃいそう
It seems like it'll go smoothly unexpectedly.
半端なら K.O. 開演準備しちゃおうか
If you're half-hearted, you'll be K.O.'d. Shall we prepare for the curtain rise?
泣いていても笑っていても愛してね
Whether crying or laughing, love me.
ほら Say No 低音響かかせろ
Come on, say no, make the bass rumble.
今宵は暗転パーティー
Tonight is a blackout party.
Woah 踊りだせ 踊りだせ 孤独は殺菌 満員御礼
Woah, start dancing, start dancing. Loneliness is sterilization, a full house.
Woah 痛みまで おシェアで ここらでバイバイ Let go
Woah, even share the pain, bye-bye for now, let go.
どんな劣等感だてて 即興の血小板で
No matter what kind of inferiority complex, with improvised platelets,
抑え込んで 突っ込んで 仕舞い込んじゃうでしょ
Suppress it, push it in, and pack it away, right?
Up and down なテンション ねえまえいちゃってんの相当
Up and down tension, man, I'm quite overwhelmed.
ドバっと噴き出すのは 本音の独り言
Bursting out in a gush is the true feeling's monologues.
「別に興味ない」 「特に関係ない」
"Not particularly interested." "Not particularly related."
塞ぎ込んで 舌鋒絶頂へ 合図を奏でて PrrPrrPrr
Hanging the head and closing up to the sharpest edge of the tongue, play the signal PrrPrrPrr.
ほら集まって夜行だ 鳴らいでいこう
Come on, gather up, it's a nocturnal crowd, let's cry out.
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-hearted, you'll be K.O.'d.
ロールケーキサンデー
Roll cake Sunday,
サンドイッチマンデー
sandwich Monday.
気分次第でいい
Whatever I'm feeling is fine,
期待半分 確率イーブン
half expectations, even odds.
明日はこれから
Tomorrow starts from here,
ネコとか(Ole!)
with cats or (Ole!)
すすきが(Ole!)
pampas grass or (Ole!)
手まねきしてる
beckoning to us.
何もない(オレ!?)
Nothing at all (Me!?)
つまんない(オレ!?)
How boring (Me!?)
今日はさようなら
Today is goodbye,
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
わたしが太陽(アイヤイヤ)
I am the sun (Ayaiya)
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
この指一本で
with just this single finger,
宇宙も 惑星も ルーレットシアター
both the universe and planets, roulette theater!
ほっ!?
Huh!?
箸転げても
Whether chopsticks roll,
達磨コケても
or daruma dolls fall,
ただ笑い転げて
just rolling with laughter.
右へとフワリ 左ヘウラリ
Floating softly right, fluttering left,
今日も歩いた
walking today too.
暗いと(ププン!) 不満を(ププン!)言うくらいなら
If you're going to complain about the dark (Pupun!)
電気を(パチン!) つければ(パチン!)いいじゃないのよ
why not just turn on the lights (Pachin!)?
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
町娘まわる(アレアレアレ)
town girls spinning (Are are are)
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
いつもより多めに
more than usual!
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
わたしが太陽(アイヤイヤ)
I am the sun (Ayaiya)
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
寿司ネタもカワク(トロ一丁!)
even sushi toppings dry out (Toro, one order!)
緑の電車も(在来線!)
even the green train (Conventional line!)
グルグルまわっていく
Spinning round and round,
神様に手を合わせてみたところで
even after putting our hands together in prayer to the gods,
鉛筆をころがして決めているよ
deciding by rolling a pencil.
宇宙も 惑星も ルーレットシアター…あれ!?
Both the universe and planets, roulette theater... ...huh!?
おどりだせ おどりだせ
Dance, dance,
この先景色満開 御立派!
scenery in full bloom ahead, magnificent!
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
今宵もアットホームパーティ!(イエー!)
tonight is also an at-home party (Yeah!)
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
また脳の髄を焦がして ププププ ププププ イエーイエ!
burning our brain marrow once again...
ほら集まって 夜行だー!
look, gather around, it's a night train!
まわる まわっていく(アイヤイヤ)
spinning, spinning round (Ayaiya)
じかんまでもお元気で ここらでバイバイレッツゴー!
stay well until the time comes, bye-bye for now, let's go!
はあー！ということで！
Haah! So,
ポルカが来てくれました！ えー、おまりぽるかでした！
Polka came to join us! Uh, it was Marine and Polka!
ポルカでしたー！ イェーイ！
It was Polka! Yay!
いやちょっと、バブみが溢れてる。
Man, it's overflowing with baby energy.
いやバブたちが
No, the babies—
色合いがさ、ちょうどいいよね、この衣装。
The color scheme is just right for this outfit.
そうなのエリー？
Is that so, Ellie?
そうなの、このステージ。ステージとね、しかもなんか、船長とポルカって結構さ、揃ったらさ
That's right, this stage. Plus Captain and Polka, when they match up,
うちら無敵感あるじゃん？
we feel invincible, right?
え、何？ バブたち？ バブたちだよね！
Eh, what? The babies? The babies, right!
ずっとバブだよね！
Always babies, right!
ポルカとの思い出全然ないけどな。
Though I have zero memories with Polka.
最悪だな、お前帰れよ！
That's awful, go home you!
お前が帰れよ！ お前だよ！
You go home! It's you!
お前が帰るの！ 手順が！
You're the one going home! The steps!
待って待って、情緒の尺があるから！
Wait wait, we have to manage our emotional pacing!
尺とか言うなよ！ もうちょっと話そうよ！
Don't call it pacing! Let's talk a bit more!
言うなよ！ あのさ、どこに出行するの、でもこれって？ え、なんか、どっか行っちゃうの？
Don't say that! Say, where are we setting sail to, anyway? Eh, are we going somewhere?
君の心に出航！
Setting sail into your heart!
ポルカも出航したくなってきた。
Polka's starting to want to set sail too.
ポルカもなんか出航したくなってきた。
Polka's also feeling like setting sail.
出航が欲しいムード。 マリンで出航したいそうだな。
A mood that wants a sail. Marine seems to want to set sail.
え、ちょっとそれ淫語だからやめてください！
Eh, hold on, that's suggestive language so please stop!
なんナンだよ！ 出航って何なんだよ！
What is it! What even is setting sail!
じゃあここで聞くけどさ。
Well then I'll ask here.
え、ここで今ここで言うんですか？
Eh, are you saying it right here and now?
あ、ごめんなさいごめんなさい、時間なんであの、ポルカ帰りまーす！
Ah, sorry sorry, it's time so, Polka is going home!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
あ、尺が！ いや、まだ尺がある！
Ah, the pacing! No, there's still pacing!
バイバーイ！ ああ、しゅっこう！ やらせるな！
Bye-bye! Ah, setting sail! Don't make me say it!
なにすっこう！ やらせろ！ なにすっこう！ やらせろ！ なんしか
What setting sail! Let me say it! What setting sail! Let me say it! Anyway...
太陽はさんさん 大航海日和だ
The sun is bright, perfect weather for a voyage.
正しさとは 愚かさとは それが何か見せつけてやる
What is correctness, what is foolishness, I'll show you what it is.
ちっちゃな頃から優等生 気づいたら大人になってた
An honor student since I was little, before I knew it I became an adult.
ナイフ様な思考回路 持ち合わせる訳もなく
A thought process like a knife, no reason to have it.
でも遊び足りない 何か足りない 困ちまう これは誰かのせい
But not playing enough, something's missing, I'm in trouble, is this someone's fault?
あてもなく ただ混乱するエデイ
Aimlessly, just confusing A-day.
それもそっか 最新の流行は当然の把握
Is that so? Naturally grasping the latest trends.
経済の動向も通勤時チェック 純情な精神で入社しワーク 社会人じゃ当然のルールです
Checking economic trends during commute, joining with pure spirit, natural rule as a working adult.
はぁ!?
Huh!?
うっせぇわ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ あなたが思うより健康です 一切合切 凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね 嗚呼 よく似合う その可も不可もないメロディー うっせぇわ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ 頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
Shut up, shut up, shut up! I'm healthier than you think. Everything's mediocre, you might not know it. Ah, that mediocre melody suits you well. Shut up, shut up, shut up! My brain works differently so there's no problem.
ついてても私模範人間 殴ったりするのはノーセンキュー だったら言葉の銃口を
Even so, I'm a model human, hitting people is no thank you. In that case, point the muzzle of words—
その頭に突き付けて撃てば マジヤバない？ 止まられやしない
at their head and shoot, isn't that really dangerous? Unstoppable.
不平不満垂れて成れの果て サディスティックに変貌する精神
Complaining and hanging down, turning into a sadistic spirit.
クソだりぃな 酒が空いたグラスあればすぐに注げ なさけない 皆がつまみ易いように串外しなさい 会計や注文は先陣を切る 文句言い最低限のマナーです
That's shit. Pour right away if an empty glass, remove from skewer for everyone, take the lead in orders, minimum manners.
はぁ!?
Huh!?
うっせぇわ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ くせぇ口塞げや限界です 絶対絶対 現代の代弁者は私やろがい もう見飽きたわ 二番煎じ言い換えのパロディ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ 丸々としたその顔面にバツ
Shut up, shut up, shut up! Shut your stinking mouth, it's the limit! Definitely the modern representative is me! I'm tired of seeing second-hand parodies! Shut up, shut up, shut up! Put an X on that plump face!
うっせぇわ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ あなたが思うより健康です 一切合切 凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね 嗚呼 つまらねぇ 何回聞かせるんだそのメモリー うっせぇわ うっせぇわ うっせぇわ アタシも大概だけどどうだっていいぜ 問題はナシ
Shut up, shut up, shut up! I'm healthier than you think. Everything's mediocre, you might not know it. Ah, how boring, how many times do I have to hear that memory? Shut up, shut up, shut up! I'm about the same, but whatever, no problem!
正しさとは 愚かさとは
What is rightness? What is stupidity?
それがなにか見せつけてやる
I will show you what they are.
ちっちゃな頃から優等生
I was an honor student since I was little,
気付いたら大人になっていた
Before I knew it, I had grown up.
ナイフのような思考回路
A train of thought like a knife,
持ち合わせる訳もなく
Which I didn't have with me.
でも遊び足りない 何か足りない
But I'm not having enough fun, something's missing.
困っちまう これは誰かのせい
These troubles better be somebody's fault,
あてどもなく ただ混乱するエイデイ
I'm just confused err day.
それもそうか
Well, is that so?
最新の流行は当然の把握
Understanding the latest trends,
経済の動向も通勤時チェック
Checking stock market on my way to work.
純情な精神で入社しワーク
Joining a company with pure spirit,
社会人じゃ当然のルールです
These are the obvious rules for us workers.
はぁ！？ うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Huh?! Shut up, shut up, shut the fuck up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切 凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね
You are too mediocre to understand me, perhaps.
あぁ よく似合う
Ah, you are a perfect match
その可もなく不可もないメロディー
To those ordinary melodies of yours.
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut the fuck up!
頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
I deal things differently so no problem at all!
つっても私模範人間
Yeah, I'm an exemplary person,
殴ったりするのはノーセンキュー
So "no thanks" to actually punching someone.
だったら言葉の銃口を
If I'll point my muzzle of words
その頭に突き付けて撃てば
To your head and fire,
マジヤバない！？ とまれやしない
Wouldn't that be so crazy? I can't stop.
不平不満垂れて成れの果て
Complaining and complaining till you die,
サディスティックに変貌する精神
My spirit becomes sadistic.
クソだりいな
I'm fucking tired.
酒が空いたグラスあればすぐに注ぎなさい
Pour drinks when glasses are empty,
皆がつまみ易いように串外しなさい
Take off the skewer so it's easier for everyone to eat.
会計や注文は先陣を切る
Check and order before anyone does,
不文律最低限のマナーです
These are the minimum rules for social manner.
はぁ！？ うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Huh?! Shut up, shut up, shut the fuck up!
くせぇ口塞えや限界です
Close your stinking mouth, I can't stand it.
絶対絶対現代の代弁者は私やろがい
I am the modern spokesperson,
もう見飽きたわ
I'm fed up with
二番煎じいいかげんのパロディ
Those rehash parodies of yours.
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut the fuck up!
まるまると仁王立ちしたその顔面にバツ
Draw an X on your fat face.
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut the fuck up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think.
一切合切凡庸なあなたじゃ分からないかもね
You are too mediocre to understand me, perhaps.
あぁ つまんねぇな
Ah, so boring.
なんかい回聞かせるんだそのメモリー
How many times do I have to listen to those memories of yours.
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut the fuck up!
アタシも大概だけどどうだっていいぜ問題はナシ
I know I'm not a big deal either, but no problem at all!
はい、というわけで、え、アクアとみお先輩が来てくれました！
So, Aqua and Mio-senpai have come to join us!
ありがとう！来てくれたよ〜
Thank you! You came~
せっかくこの3人で揃ったので、社会への不満は叫びましょう！
Since the three of us are gathered here, let's shout our complaints about society!
社会への不満？
Complaints about society?
社会への不満かー。じゃあ船長からいきますよ。
Complaints about society, huh. Well, Captain, you go first.
あるんだ。なんだろう。
There are some. I wonder what.
バナナスミカンの次は何だろ
What's next after bananas and oranges...
え、普通に、いい銭だったら…おいしいよ、たら！
If it's good money... cod is delicious!
社長への不満じゃんそれわ！
That's a complaint against the president!
本当だ！
That's true!
みお先輩ありますか？
Mio-senpai, do you have any?
え、なんだろうなー。うん、あ、あるあるある！
Hmm, I wonder. Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah!
やろ、いこ、いこ、いこ。はい！
Let's do it, let's go. Yes!
ええと… オオカミ！周りが逃げ遅れたら、なぜか勝手に逃げ遅れてしまう！
If everyone around is late in escaping, somehow I end up escaping late too!
あ、オオカミ社会の話。
Ah, wolf society talk.
そうそう、オオカミの…嫌だったんだね。なんか不気味だなと思って。
Right, wolf... you hated it. You thought it was kind of eerie.
え、アクアはなんかありますか？
Um, Aqua, do you have anything?
社会への不満かー。うーん、あ、わかります！
Complaints about society. Hmm, oh, I know!
うん、あ、わかります！はい。なんだろう。
Yeah, oh, I know! Yes. I wonder what.
じゃ、いいですか？お願いします。
Well, is it okay? Please go ahead.
ぼっちで何が悪い！！
What's wrong with being a loner!!
社長！あ、くった！社長！あ、くった！ぼっちじゃないよ！
President! Ah, wait! President! Ah, wait! You're not a loner!
そうだよ！友達がついてる！普通に浮いてますよ、社長！
That's right! You have friends! You're totally standing out alone, President!
すみません、ちょっともう時間なんで帰ってもらっていいですか？
Sorry, it's about time, so could you please go home?
あ、社長行きますよ。帰りましょう。帰りましょう。バイバイヤーイ！
Ah, President, let's go. Let's head back. Let's head back. Bye-bye-bye!
君は聞こえる 僕のこの声が
Do you hear my voice?
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Engulfed by the darkness, in vain.
もしもし世界が 意味を持つなら こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない?
If the world has meaning, does that mean my feelings aren't pointless either?
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
Crushed by my longing, I gave up,
果てしない空の色も 知らないで
Not even knowing what color the boundless sky was.
走り出した想いが 今でも この胸を確実に叩いているから
My feelings took off running, they're still definitely pounding on my heart.
今日の僕がその先に続く
So I'm gonna keep going today,
僕らなりの明日を構築していく
I'm gonna keep on building a future for myself.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer has always been right here.
過ぎた季節を 嘆く暇はない
I don't have time to grieve over seasons gone by,
二度と迷って しまわないように
I hope I don't lose my way ever again.
数えきれない ほんのささやかな そんな後悔 抱えたまま その背中だけ追いかけて ここまで来たんだ
With those countless, but oh so small regrets in my arms, I chased you all the way here.
探していた 僕だけにできること
I was searching for the one thing only I could do.
あの日くれた言葉が 今でも この胸に確実に届いているから
What you said to me that day still definitely is reaching my heart.
昨日よりも今日僕は 僕の生まれてきた理由に気付いていく
Today I'll be more aware why I was born than I was yesterday.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer has always been right here.
全てがまるで当たり前みたいだった 尊い日々はまだ終わらない
Those precious days when everything seemed so obvious aren't over.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer has always been right here.
君は聞こえる?
Do you hear it?
僕のこの声が
My voice
闇に虚しく 吸い込まれた
Has been engulfed by the darkness, in vain
もしもし世界が 意味を持つなら
If the world has meaning,
こんな気持ちも 無駄ではない?
does that mean my feelings aren't pointless either?
憧れに押しつぶされて あきらめてたんだ
Crushed by my longing, I had given up
果てしない空の色も 知らないで
not even knowing what color the boundless sky was.
走り出した想いが今でも
My feelings took off running,
この胸を確かに叩いているから
and they're still pounding on my heart today.
今日の僕がその先に続く
So today's me will keep going beyond that
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
and build our own tomorrow.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer has always been right here.
過ぎた季節を 嘆く暇はない
I have no time to grieve over seasons gone by,
二度と迷って しまわぬように
so I won't lose my way ever again.
数えきれない ほんのささやかな
With countless, oh so small
そんな後悔 抱えたまま
regrets held close in my arms,
その背中だけ追いかけて ここまで来たんだ
I've chased your back all the way here.
探していた 僕だけにできること
I was searching for what only I could do.
あの日くれた言葉が今でも
The words you gave me that day still
この胸に確かに届いてるから
are surely reaching deep within my heart.
昨日よりも 今日僕は僕の
Today, more than yesterday, I realize
生まれてきたわけに気付いていく
the reason why I was born.
答えはそう いつもここにある
The answer is always right here.
全てがまるで当たり前みたいだった
Everything seemed so completely natural,
尊い日々は まだ終わらない
and these precious days are not yet over.
そしてまた…
And once again...
走り出した想いが今でも
My feelings took off running,
この胸を確かに叩いているから
and they're still pounding on my heart today.
今日の僕がその先に続く
So today's me will keep going beyond that
僕らなりの明日を築いていく
and build our own tomorrow.
はーい！
Yay!
あやめ先輩もう！
Ayame-senpai, seriously!
なんか こういうライブみたいなやつ
Like, for this kind of live concert thing...
あやめ先輩と歌って踊るの もう何回目ですかね？
how many times have we sung and danced together, Ayame-senpai?
四回目ぐらい？さん？
Around the fourth time? Three?
え、それってもうかなりのラブライブ感ですよね？
Eh, that's already giving off some serious Love Live vibes, right?
え？ 今日は何て呼んでくれたの？
Eh? What did you call me today?
え、愛してるから
Uh, because I love you.
ガッツリ取り乱したて今
You totally lost your composure just now!
あやめ…
Ayame...
いや、あやめちん
No, Ayame-chin.
そのさ、あやめちんってあれ？もしかして…もしかしてあれですか？
Like, "Ayame-chin", is that... could that possibly be...?
そう、ちょっとね、物付けの動画をね、前に出していたですけど
Yeah, I put out a dubbing video a while ago, and...
カンニングしながらカンニングしながらね
while cheating, while cheating, you know...
ちょっとね、形練習してたんですけど
we were practicing the movements a bit like that.
そう、判定にしてたらね
Yeah, if you do it with motion capture evaluation...
判定したほうが踊りやすいんだよね
it's easier to dance when it judges you, right?
あやめちんマリンちんって
"Ayame-chin, Marine-chin"...
え、まさかこの話で終わる気ですか？
Eh, are we really ending on this topic?
ちょっと！時間！時間長い！
Wait! Time! We're taking too much time!
いやまだちょっと、愛してる、愛してる、愛してる！
No, wait, I love you, I love you, I love you!
ああ、あやめー！
Ah, Ayame!
ヒトリゴトだよ 恥ずかしいこと聞かないでよね
I'm just talking to myself, don't ask me embarrassing things!
キミのことだよ でもその先は言わないけどね
It's about you... but I won't say any more than that!
掛け違えてる ボタンみたいなもどかしさを
I'm so confused, like a mismatched button
ほどけないまま また難しくしようとしてる
unable to untangle it, I keep making things difficult.
掛け違えてる ボタンみたいなもどかしさを
I'm so confused, like a mismatched button
ほどけないまま また難しくしようとしてる
unable to untangle it, I keep making things difficult.
伝えたい気持ちは今日も 言葉になる直前に
The feeling I want to convey today, right before turning into words,
ヒトリゴトだよ 恥ずかしいこと聞かないでよね
It's just a monologue, so don't ask anything embarrassing!
キミノコトだよ でもその先は言わないけどね
It's about you, though I won't tell you beyond that!
君の笑顔を探しているよ
I'm searching for your smile!
無意識の中 その理由はまだ言えないけど
Unconsciously, I can't say the reason yet, but...
一人でいると会いたくなるよ
When I'm alone, I want to see you.
誰と居たって会いたくなるよ
No matter who I'm with, I want to see you.
たったヒトコト ねえ、どうして aah!
Just a single word—hey, why, ah!
言えないその言葉 言えないこの気持ち aah!
I can't say those words, I can't say this feeling, ah!
早く気づいてほしいのに!
Even though I want you to realize it soon!
1000ピースある パズルみたいな選択肢と
With 1000 puzzle-like choices
想像力が 判断力の邪魔をしちゃう
Imagination gets in the way of judgment.
つかめない気持ちは今日も
Uncatchable feelings today as well...
可愛いない顔見せて 自己嫌悪プラス後悔で
Showing an uncute face, with self-hatred plus regret,
ため込んだゴメンネを吐き出すにはほど遠い
It's a long way from spitting out the stored apologies.
耳を澄ませば聞こえてくるよ
If I strain my ears, I can hear it—
君の声だけ聞こえてくるよ
Only your voice comes through.
雑踏の中 気づかないフリをしているけど
In the hustle and bustle, I pretend not to notice, but...
隣にいると嬉しくなるよ
When you're next to me, I feel happy.
近くにいると寂しくなるよ
When you're close, I feel lonely.
単純なことでも どうして aah!
Even for simple things, why, ah!
言えないその言葉 言えないこの気持ち aah!
I can't say those words, I can't say this feeling, ah!
もっと素直になりたい
I want to be more honest.
泣き出しそうな空模様
A sky that looks like it's about to cry,
頬に一粒雨かな
Is that a single raindrop on my cheek?
不穏な体裁 心傘で隠した ひとりごとに全部隠した
I hid my uneasy appearance with an umbrella, hiding everything in a monologue.
君のこと 本当はずっと… aah!
The truth is, about you, always... ah!
ふとした時に探しているよ
Searching for you when I least expect it,
君の笑顔を探しているよ
Searching for your smile.
無意識の中 その理由はまだ言えないけど
Unconsciously, I can't say the reason yet, but...
一人でいると会いたくなるよ
When I'm alone, I want to see you.
誰と居たって会いたくなるよ
No matter who I'm with, I want to see you.
たったヒトコト ねえ、どうして aah!
Just a single word—hey, why, ah!
言えないその言葉 言えないこの気持ち aah!
I can't say those words, I can't say this feeling, ah!
早く気づいてほしいのに!
Even though I want you to realize it soon!
お疲れ様！曲作ってくれてありがとう！
Good work! Thank you for writing the song!
いやなんかすごい船長ってことねここね、ここ。
Marine is amazing here, right here.
あ、そうだよ。
Ah, that's right.
乗せてやろうか、この船に。
Shall I let you board this ship?
いや、もうリールはいいよ。
No, reels are fine.
ちょっと待って待って！まだ早いよね。
Wait, wait! It's still early.
お話しよう、お話！
Let's talk, let's talk!
いやでも「ヒトリゴト」っていうさ、曲さ、ぺこーちゃんがね提案してくれたんだよね。
But you know, Pekora proposed the song "Hitorigoto", right?
あれ、その曲って、ぺこーちゃ、あれ、忘れないで！
Wait, that song... Pekora, wait, don't forget!
え、でもぺこーちゃん思ったの、一緒にさ、歌って踊って、ぺこマリでえもくできるんだって。
But Pekora thought, if we sing and dance together as PekoMari, we can make it emotional.
なに、エモくできるんだって。
What, you can make it emotional.
なるよ、いつだって！ほら、今エモい、エモいウチら。
It always will! Look, we're emotional right now.
エモいウチらのさ、なんか、あいさつ笑い、なんか、微妙なこう...
Our emotional... greeting laughs, sort of subtle...
笑って笑って、はい、チーズ！
Laugh, laugh, ready, cheese!
ねえ！嘘くさい！嘘くさいね、笑顔が！
Hey! So fake! Your smile is so fake!
いやでもこの歌ね、あのデコーラさんが、二人で歌ってってなった時、ぺこだからさ...
But this song, you know, when Decorah-san said let's sing together, since it's Peko...
ぺこ、二人で歌えりゃ曲ってなんかあるかなと思った時にさ、この曲いいじゃんって思って、ぺこちゃんが提案したらマリンも乗っかってくれたから、めっちゃ嬉しかったぺこだよ。
When I wondered if there's any song two people could sing, I thought this song would be great, and when I proposed it, Marine went along with it, so I was super happy, Peko.
今終わらせようとしてるでしょ？
You're trying to wrap it up now, right?
まだ終わらせないよ！まだまだ！
Not ending it yet! Not yet!
そろそろ時間だって。二人のおもろい話とかして、ぺこマリは真実！ぺこマリは真実！
They're saying it's almost time. Tell some funny stories of us two—PekoMari is the truth! PekoMari is the truth!
お別れだ。
It's time to part.
てをつなごう 一緒に笑おう
Let's join hands, let's laugh together,
ともだちになろう
Let's become friends!
ぼくの右手と 君の左手を
My right hand and your right hand—
つないでみたら なんだかうれしくなったよ
When we connected them, for some reason I felt so happy!
ぼくの右手と 君の右手で
My right hand and your right hand—
あくしゅうをしたら さみしくなくなったよ
When we shook hands, I wasn't lonely anymore!
みぎてのひとひだりてともだちひと...
Right hand, left hand, friends with everyone...
国や 言葉 など 関係 ない の さ
It doesn't matter what country or language...
出会え た 事 こそ 一生 の 宝物
Meeting you is a lifetime treasure!
一人 じゃ ない から 心強く なる
Because we're not alone, we become strong!
手 を つなごう
Let's join hands,
いっしょにわらおう
let's smile together.
ともだちになろうよ
Let's become friends!
てをつなごう こころつなごう
Let's join hands, let's join hearts.
ぼくらはなかまたち
We are companions!
ぼくの小指と きみの小指で
Let's promise with our pinky fingers,
約束しよう いつまでも仲良し
we'll stay good friends forever!
つらい時も ケンカをして も 離れていても
Even on painful times when we fight and drift apart,
ぼくたちはともだち
we are friends!
きっ と 世界中 が
I'm sure the whole world
みんな ともだち に なれる よ
will become friends!
手 を つなごう
Let's join hands,
いっしょにわらおう
let's smile together,
ともだちになろうよ
let's become friends!
てをつなごう こころつなごう
Let's join hands, let's join hearts.
ぼくらはなかまたち
We are companions!
手 を つなごう
Let's join hands,
いっしょにわらおう
let's smile together,
ともだちになろうよ
let's become friends!
てをつなごう こころつなごう
Let's join hands, let's join hearts.
ぼくらはなかまたち
We are companions!
手 を つなごう
Let's join hands,
いっしょにわらおう
let's smile together,
ともだちになろうよ
let's become friends!
てをつなごう てをつなごう
Let's join hands, let's join hands.
ぼくらはなかまたち
We are companions!
てをつなごう
Let's join hands!
ゲーマーズの戌神ころねです！
I'm Korone from Gamers!
たてんしのにんげん…、いや。雪花のラミィです！
I'm Lamy from Gen 5!
５期生の、雪花のラミィです！ ３期の、宝鐘マリンです！
And I'm Marine from Gen 3!
３期の、白銀ノエルです！
I'm Noel from Gen 3!
なかよしすてっぷ！
Let's get along!
うちだってけっこう裏で話すから、もう話すことないんだよね。
Well, we talk about everything backstage, so we don't really have anything left to talk about!
じゃあ、開催しました！
So, the live is basically over!
ありがとうございました！バイバーイ！
Thank you very much! Bye-bye!
３、２、１、あ… なっちゃって？
Three, two, one, and...
で、何話すんだっけ？
What are we supposed to talk about again?
あ、今日のさ、目的は何だっけ？
Oh right, today's purpose!
そうだよ、なんで呼ばれたのかわかってないよ、だんだん。
That's right, why were we called here?
実はね、船長ちょっと…し、あ、ちょっと、言えないけど…し、言えないの？
Well, you see... the captain has a... well, I shouldn't say it, but...
重大発表があって…
A major announcement!
なに？え、何々？聞かせて、聞かせて！
What? What? Let me hear it!
実は…この次、発表なんですよ！え！？本当！？
Actually... the next announcement is happening right after this!
この後すぐ！？本当！？
Right after this? Seriously?
じゃあ早く見たいからもう終わるか。
Well, if we want to see it quickly, we should just end the stream!
そうね、じゃあ開催して。
Right, let's end it!
ありがとうございました！バイバーイ！
Thank you very much! Bye-bye!
３、２、１、あ、なっちゃって！
Three, two, one, and... oops!
みんな…
Everyone...
私のもの そう私のもの
Mine, yes, my mine,
千の黄金
a thousand golds.
数百年の財宝 この船に眠る
Centuries of treasure sleep in this ship.
古びた伝説は 呪われた幽霊船に
The ancient legend leads to a cursed ghost ship
続く夜の潮路
along the night's tide.
そこに富が残る 海賊の夢があるのなら
If there's wealth left, if there's a pirate's dream,
頂くしかないでしょ?
you have to take it, don't you?
無謀な赤よ 若き盗人よ
Oh reckless red, oh young thief,
命をもっテ 後悔に代えさせてやろう
I'll make you pay for it with your life.
止まない雨の弾丸で
With unrelenting bullet rain,
駆け来る鼓動 まだこの足走れるはず
Racing heartbeat, these legs should still be able to run
美しいほど この瞳焦がす 生命の炎
So beautiful, the flame of life scorching these eyes,
ガーネットの色彩 掠め 宝石ななら
Grazing the garnet colors, if they are jewels,
ガーネットの色彩 貴方にはない
Garnet hues that you do not possess.
私のもの そう私のもの 奪ってみろ
Mine, yes, my mine, try and take them.
命の証を 貴方の求める全てを
The proof of life, everything you desire.
輝きはくすんで 錆びついて
The brilliance fades, rusting away,
それでも 泥舟にしがみつくなら
yet if you cling to a sinking ship,
泡沫と共に沈め
sink along with the bubbles.
黒い帆に 隠れる
Hidden in the black sails,
“極上の海賊の秘宝”
“The supreme pirate's treasure”
マリン出航！！ 作詞:砂守岳央 作曲:田中公平
[Title: Marine Shukkou!! / Lyrics: Takeo Sunamori, Music: Kohei Tanaka]
世界が 壊れてゆく
The world is breaking apart,
懐かしい声が 聞こえていた
a nostalgic voice could be heard.
汚れタ拳 痛むほど 強く握った
Clenching my bruised fist so hard it aches,
当たり前に笑っていた昨日は もうどこにもない
Yesterday, when I smiled so naturally, is nowhere to be found.
明日がどんな日になるのか 誰も知らない
No one knows what kind of day tomorrow will be.
稼ぎにさえ見捨てられた今日を取り戻すこと誓う
I swear to take back today, abandoned even by earnings.
錨上げ
Raise the anchor,
世界の果てへ 旅立とう
let's set sail to the end of the world!
嵐の海
To the stormy sea,
立ち上がれ
stand up!
幸せは望めば
If you wish for happiness,
手に入るほど 弱くはない
it's not weak enough to just fall into your hands.
守るために戦うなら 楽園なんて
If you fight to protect it, a paradise like that
ならなくていい
doesn't even need to be.
誰がいい 誰が悪者とか
Who is good, who is the villain—
切り返すこともできない
there's no turning back from that.
捨てられた 簡単に
Easily discarded,
灰の中 消えてしまう 奇跡を ただ見ることが 許されないなら
if we aren't even allowed to just witness the miracle vanishing in the ashes,
ひとりきりで震えていた 弱い自分 じゃあはしない
I won't be that weak self trembling all alone anymore,
それでも決意 胸に抱けば もう迷わない
yet if I hold resolve in my chest, I will hesitate no more.
道半ばで 倒れたともに
To the comrades who fell halfway,
託された 言葉抱き
embracing the words entrusted to me.
錨上げ 自由の旗上げ
Raise the anchor, raise the flag of freedom!
大海原 燃え上がれ どんな雨だろとも
Burn up, vast ocean, no matter what rain falls,
ひるむことなく 炎になれ
without flinching, become the flame!
錨上げ 自由の旗上げ
Raise the anchor, raise the flag of freedom!
大海原 燃え上がれ どんな雨だろとも
Burn up, vast ocean, no matter what rain falls,
ひるむことなく 炎になれ
without flinching, become the flame!
よほほはーろへー よほほはーろへー
Heave-ho, heave-ho...
待ち焦がれの勝利の悧得
Waiting eagerly for the spoils of victory,
立ち上がれ よほほはーろへー...
stand up, heave-ho...
おいで！ いざなる
Come on! Now is the time
快速だんだん 光あれえ！
Full speed ahead, let there be light!
光あれえ！
Let there be light!
出航！！
Set sail!!
船長の新曲「マリン出航！！」
The Captain's new song, "Marine Shukkou!!"
船長が一番好きな楽曲を田中公平先生に作っていただきました！
was composed by Kohei Tanaka, the Captain's favorite!
本日24時から各種音楽サイトにて配信開始！
Streaming begins tonight at midnight on all music platforms!
そしてこのあとすぐアニメミュージックビデオプレミア公開です！
And right after this, the anime music video premieres!
それではいきますよ、出航ー！
Here we go, set sail!